{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "A founder of this philosophy posited that the ultimate horror is \"being trampled to death by geese\" and used the metaphor of crop rotation to explain how aesthetes live. This philosophy, which was equated with \"a humanism\" by a French proponent, was originated by Soren Kierkegaard. For 10 points, name this philosophy of Albert Camus and Jean-Paul Sartre.",
      "answer": "existentialism"
    },
    {
      "question": "This author created analogies of the divided line and the Sun in a work featuring his brothers, Adeimantus and Glaucon. This man, who was briefly sold into slavery on Syracuse, developed a theory of eternal forms and compared the city to the soul in a work that advocated rule by philosopher-kings. For ten points, name this Greek philosopher who recorded his teacher, Socrates, in dialogues like The Apology and wrote The Republic.",
      "answer": "Plato"
    },
    {
      "question": "Description acceptable. In one work, one individual with this role has to be replaced by Polus and then Callicles, all of whom argue that rhetoric is superior to philosophy. In another work, a person who performs this role gives a hypothetical argument about justice’s origins as a means to an end. That individual, Glaucon, takes on this role after Thrasymachus, another of these people, fails to convince a man that justice is the “interest of the stronger.” For ten points, identify this role, in which people served as sounding boards for a certain ancient Athenian philosopher.",
      "answer": [
        "interlocutors of Socrates",
        "descriptive answers such as “people who talk to or argue with, etc. Socrates”"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In this work, a character recounts the tale of a man named Er who revives on his funeral pyre and shares an account of the afterlife. A character in this work tries to explain the psyche by asking Glaucon to imagine a divided line and imagines a ring that makes the wearer invisible, the Ring of Gyges. The Allegory of the Cave and the benefits of rule under a “philosopher-king” are described in, for ten points, what Platonic dialogue about justice and forms of government like oligarchy and democracy?",
      "answer": "The Republic or Politeia"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man was able to flee Nazi Germany after his consultation and analysis of the royal Princess Marie Bonaparte led to a lifelong friendship between the two. The heiress to Tiffany & Co., Dorothy Burlingham, was in a relationship with this man's daughter and fellow psychoanalyst, Anna. This man developed the idea of the id, ego, and superego, which were founding ideas of psychoanalysis. For ten points, name this Austrian psychologist who wrote The Interpretation of Dreams.",
      "answer": "Sigmund Freud or Sigismund Schlomo Freud 2021-22 B-Set History Bowl - 2021-11-03 Round 2"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man anticipated Ricardo's iron law of wages in his The Present High Price of Provisions. A modern disciple of this man's ideas is Paul Ehrlich. This man claimed that \"preventative checks\" such as birth control were the only way to avoid his namesake catastrophe. For 10 points, name this economist who predicted population would outstrip food supply.",
        "answer": "Thomas Malthus"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Malthus was one of the few political economists to support what set of laws, which placed tarriffs on imported grain?",
        "answer": "Corn Laws"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man left his job after his employer was seduced by 80 dancing girls. This philosopher argued that words must be made to fit reality through a process of “rectification of names,” and his Five Relationships included ones between father and son and brother to brother. This man, who served under the Prince of Lu, believed in cultivating a trait known as “ren”. For ten points, name this Chinese philosopher, the author of the Analects.",
        "answer": [
          "Confucius",
          "Kong Zi"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Qin dynasty ended a period in Chinese philosophy that purportedly contained “this many” Schools of Thought. Mao Zedong later asked for this many flowers to bloom before crushing that campaign with the Anti-Rightist Movement.",
        "answer": [
          "100",
          "Hundred Schools of Thought",
          "Hundred Flowers Campaign"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man's wife was the Russian ballerina Lydia Lopokova, and his brother injected radium chloride to fight breast cancer tumors. This man proposed a logical-relationist theory of probability in a 1921 treatise. This man introduced the ideas of the consumption function while denying that the economy would adapt to give full employment, instead believing in booms and panics. This author wrote The General Theory of Employment, Interest and Money. For ten points, name this English economist who opposed Classical Economics.",
        "answer": [
          "John Maynard Keynes",
          "1st Baron Keynes"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Keynes coined the term for this law which states that production is the source of demand. It is named for a Frenchman who studded entrepreneurial economics.",
        "answer": "Say's Law"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Versailles",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Sun King who moved the court to Versailles.",
          "answer": "Louis XIV"
        },
        {
          "question": "war ended by the Treaty of Versailles.",
          "answer": "World War I"
        },
        {
          "question": "glassy hall where the Treaty of Versailles was signed.",
          "answer": "Hall of Mirrors or Galerie des Glaces"
        },
        {
          "question": "economist who attended the Versailles talks and wrote The Economic Consequences of the Peace.",
          "answer": "John Maynard Keynes"
        },
        {
          "question": "queen who received the Petit Trianon chateau at Versailles as a gift – hers to enjoy before she was executed.",
          "answer": "Marie Antoinette"
        },
        {
          "question": "Parisian royal residence replaced by Versailles, whose gardens later became a public park.",
          "answer": "Tuileries Palace or Tuileries Gardens"
        },
        {
          "question": "aristocratic political system whose excesses led to the building of Versailles and the French Revolution.",
          "answer": [
            "Ancien Regime or Old Regime",
            "Bourbon Dynasty"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "room requested by Louis-Philippe to commemorate France’s millitary?",
          "answer": "Hall of Battles or Galerie des Batallies"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Plato",
      "prompt": "In the life and career of Plato, name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Academic discipline he revolutionized, whose Greek name translates as “love of wisdom” and which studies the nature of knowledge and existence.",
          "answer": [
            "philosophy",
            "word forms"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Greek city where Plato taught students at the Academy.",
          "answer": "Athens"
        },
        {
          "question": "Mentor of Plato, who was condemned to death for corrupting the youth of Athens.",
          "answer": "Socrates"
        },
        {
          "question": "Poisonous plant used to kill that mentor, as recounted in Plato’s dialogue Phaedo.",
          "answer": [
            "hemlock",
            "descriptions of drinking hemlock"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Student of Plato and founder of the Peripatetic school who tutored Alexander the Great.",
          "answer": "Aristotle"
        },
        {
          "question": "Sicilian city where Plato advised Dionysius [die-oh-niss-ee-us] the Younger.",
          "answer": "Syracuse"
        },
        {
          "question": "Dialogue by Plato that describes the ideal city-state and cites the timocracy of Sparta as the second-best kind of state.",
          "answer": "The Republic"
        },
        {
          "question": "Dialogue by Plato in which Aristophanes, Alcibiades, and other prominent people drunkenly discuss the nature of love.",
          "answer": "The Symposium"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This philosopher asked “What is the meaning of ascetic ideals?” in the third essay of a book On the Genealogy of Morality, which was a follow-up to Beyond Good and Evil. This thinker was horrified by the (20 pts)",
        "“eternal recurrence,” and he thought that the “will to power” was the driving force of life. This philosopher wrote a parable about an insane man with a lantern in (10 pts)",
        "The Gay Science. For ten points, name this German philosopher who wrote Thus Spoke Zarathustra, an important influence on Nazism who originated the phrase “God is dead.”"
      ],
      "answer": "Friedrich Nietzsche"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This thinker thought that the “sublime” was the feeling of experiencing something that feels infinite when one rationally knows that it is not. This philosopher defined the title concept as “man’s (20 pts)",
        "emergence from his self-imposed immaturity” in an essay asking “What Is Enlightenment?” This thinker explored the moral law in his (10 pts)",
        "Metaphysics of Morals and the earlier Groundwork. For ten points, name this German philosopher who formulated the categorical imperative and wrote the Critique of Pure Reason."
      ],
      "answer": "Immanuel Kant"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In The Open Society and Its Enemies, Karl Popper claimed that this philosopher’s political thought contained all the elements of totalitarianism. In a work written by this philosopher, a man discusses the role of piety in his decision to prosecute his father. In addition to (20 pts)",
        "Euthyphro [youth-ih-fro], this philosopher wrote a work featuring the (10 pts)",
        "Allegory of the Cave. For ten points, name this author of The Republic whose dialogues depict the teachings of his mentor, Socrates."
      ],
      "answer": "Plato or Platon"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Because of this man’s system of natural philosophy, Gisbert Voetius [[GIZ- behrt VEE-tee-ooss]] persuaded the University of Utrecht [[YOO-trekt]] to condemn this man, who retaliated with the publication of Comments on a Certain Broadsheet. Using the (20 pts)",
        "“Wax Example,” this man theorized that things are perceived through our intellect, and he believed deductive reasoning proved God’s (10 pts)",
        "existence. This man developed a system to plot points on a namesake plane. For ten points, name this French mathematician and philosopher whose views are best exemplified by his quote, “I think therefore I am.”"
      ],
      "answer": "René Descartes ] or Renatus Cartesius"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In Galen's [[GAY-lens]] work On Fallacies, he criticized this philosophical school's inability to use clear language and their disbelief in the duality of the soul. The emperor Domitian [[doh-MIH-shun]] banished one of this school's philosophers, Epictetus [[eh-PIK-teh-tus]], (20 pts)",
        "who returned to Greece and taught Arrian. \"Virtue is the only good\" was often espoused by supporters of this philosophical school. Zeno (10 pts)",
        "of Citium founded, for ten points, what school of philosophy which includes the writer of Meditations, Emperor Marcus Aurelius?"
      ],
      "answer": "Stoicism or Stoics"
    }
  ]
}